ALEX ZDATNY

732-887-3198 alexzdatny@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/alex-zdatny github.com/alcasinoroyale Blog: alexzdatny.com Portfolio: alexzdatny.me

Full Stack Developer with a passion for content creation, user experience, and building applications. I discovered web development while studying Journalism and creating multi-media packages for feature stories. After becoming immersed in coding as a content developer for an analytics startup, I decided to expand my skill set through The Flatiron School. I'm excited to code, collaborate, and learn while helping tech companies evolve.

EXPERIENCE

ChefMod, LLC, New York, NY

Software Engineer (Contractor), December 2019 - present

- + Revitalize Vendor Portal UI utilizing Angular and Typescript to improve functionality and user experience
- + Working with client API to implement security services for login and user data components
- + Collaborate with marketing and senior engineers for application design and deployment

Bed, Bath, & Beyond, Watchung, NJ

Sales Associate, August 2017 - July 2018

+ Specialized in all areas of the store managing in-store and online sales

Know Your Audience, Brooklyn, NY

Content Developer, March 2016 - June 2017

- + Published 20+ articles focused on tech trends and consumer applications
- + Curated tech industry data and researched graphics relative for content creators
- + Promoted company brand and tech convention appearances across all social media channels

AT&T, Bedminster, NJ

Digital Marketing Intern, Spring 2016

+ Assisted Marketing Communications Manager and participated in meetings for review of interactive sales tools

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQL, JavaScript, React, Redux, Angular, TypeScript, Bootstrap, Atom, JQuery, NodeJS, WordPress, Final Cut Pro, Adobe Photoshop

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Renecades Gameroom - GitHub | Youtube Demo

Create and Play Games, Earn Rewards, Climb the Leaderboard

- + Constructed a Rails API for players to build exclusive gaming profiles
- + Utilized Active Record to manipulate data and perform database operations
- + Engineered OAuth Feature to provide access for Facebook logins
- + Incorporated JavaScript features for customization, styling, and efficiency

Reel 2 Real - GitHub | Youtube Demo

Search and Build a List of your Favorite Films

- + Integrated a Rails API with React-Redux frontend through TheMovieDB
- + Created class and functional components to handle user interaction
- + Implemented actions and reducers to control user and film functions
- + Designed user interface combining Bootstrap and CSS styling

The Itinerary Hub - GitHub | Youtube Demo

An organized itinerary builder for occasional and frequent travelers

- + Developed a Sinatra API for users to create multiple itineraries
- + Implemented MVC framework to structure the user interface and backend
- + Utilized Active Record for validations and storing user data

EDUCATION

The Flatiron School - New York, NY - 2019

+ Certificate, Full Stack Web Development

Rider University - Lawrenceville, NJ - 2016

+ Bachelor's Degree: Journalism - GPA: 3.5, Cum Laude